pennnet.com 2014-12-20

# Privacy Policy - Pennwell Corporate

PennWell believes in protecting your privacy.  We have procedures in place to ensure that we adhere to the latest privacy practices including adhering to state laws (California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance), Federal laws (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act), and International agreements (U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework). 

### What information do we collect?

When you visit one of our websites or other digital services, we may collect anonymous or personally identifiable information from you. Personally identifiable information (PII) is information that can identify you, such as your full name, email address, postal address, telephone number, and fax number. In some cases, you may provide information to us, and in other cases information about you or your activities on our Services may be automatically collected.

When you provide information to us by registering on one of our websites subscribing to one of our newsletters, responding to a survey, filling out a form  or voluntarily providing any other information across any of our digital services, we may choose to capture that information.

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number or credit card information.

When you download or use apps created by us or our subsidiaries, we may receive information about your location, app usage and your mobile device.  We may use this information to provide you with location-based or other services.

### What do we use your information for and what is the purpose of collecting it?

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience
  * To improve our website
  * To process your orders or requests and to pre-populate forms
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature
  * To send periodic emails

·        To match the right messages to you on our sites or on third party sites

The information you provide may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order.  In addition, you may receive related company news, updates, and product or service information, etc.

Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.  You may also reach us via our Customer Service Form.

### How do we protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your personal information. We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.

After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) will not be kept on file for more than 60 days.

### Do we use cookies?

Yes we use cookies.  Cookies are small files that a site, or its service provider, transfers to your device through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information

We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits.  We use information gathered through analytics tools that utilize cookies to aggregate anonymized user information to help us better design our Sites, and to enhance the functionality you enjoy as you navigate between our digital services.

We also may use cookies to match the right people with the right message you see on our Services or on third-party sites in conjunction with third-party advertising companies.

By using our site or allowing your browser to “accept cookies”, you consent to use of cookies with respect to your device.

### Do we disclose any information to outside parties?

PennWell does provide your personally identifiable information to (i) trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential, and (ii) trusted third parties with whom PennWell contracts with to provide you services and products whereby, in such instances, notice will be provided to you before such services or products are purchased. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. 

### Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

### California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act.  Protecting consumer privacy is important to PennWell. 

### U.S. - EU Safe Harbor Self- Certified

When we collect personal information from you on your website, we adhere to the U.S. –EU Safe Harbor Framework concerning the transfer of personal data from the European Union (“EU”) to the United States of America.  Accordingly, we follow the Safe Harbor Principles published by the U.S. Department of Commerce with respect to all such data. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy, rules set by the Department of Commerce will prevail.

To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view PennWell’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

### Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act) and children under the age of 13 are not eligible to use the services of this site. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years of age or older.

### Online Privacy Policy Only

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.

### Terms and Conditions

Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website at <http://www.pennwell.com/index/terms.html>

### Your Consent

By using our site, you consent to our online privacy policy.

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below.

### Updating Personal Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, or request deletion on our site by submitting your request via this form to our customer service team.  We will respond to requests within 30 days. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

### Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy or complaints about our websites you may contact us using the information below.

1421 S. Sheridan  
Tulsa, OK 74112  
United States  
Website:  [www.pennwell.com](http://www.pennwell.com/)  
Email:  Complete form  
Phone:  800-331-4463

**_European Consumers_**

As part of the Safe Harbor self-certification, the Direct Marketing Association acts as PennWell’s dispute resolution mediator.  If you believe we have not adequately resolved your data questions, feel free to contact the Direct Marketing Association.

Safe Harbor Line  
Direct Marketing Association  
1615 L Street, NW - Suite 1100  
Washington, DC 20036  
Website:  [www.dmaresponsibility.org/safeharbor/consumers.shtml](http://www.dmaresponsibility.org/safeharbor/consumers.shtml)  
Email:  [safeharbor@the-dma.org](mailto:safeharbor@the-dma.org)  
Fax:  202.955.0085

Last Updated:  October 7, 2014
